(いびき)
(銀時)んんっ…｡
[Hey! Main character, wake up! Feeling lazy today, jerk?!]
[Start your own damn show if you're done with this one!]
[An Urgent Special Program]
(犬の遠吠え)
♪♪～
The great city of Edo.
＜大都会 江戸｡
[Kabukicho 1st Street]
夜なお 喧騒と欲望を糧に➡
Every night, people are drawn here in search of excitement and titillation,
人々を 誘蛾灯のように
いざなう街｡
like moths to a flame.
[Karaoke House]
そして…＞
Then...
(ﾊﾟﾄｶｰのｻｲﾚﾝ)
[Shinsengumi]
Third Squad, go around the back! Tenth Squad, follow me!
(原田)三番隊は 裏を固めろ！
十番隊は 私に続け!!
(ｶﾗｵｹ)
Oh... Katoken Samba!
＜ そんな 江戸の街に
梁跳跋扈する 反乱分子や➡
In Edo there is a special armed police force that serves the government.
They deal swiftly with rebellious elements that run wild in the city.
闇の世界に暗躍する
攘夷志士たちを 即時 処分する➡
幕府直属の
特殊武装警察があった＞
And with exclusionists who engage in shady activities in the underworld.
♪♪(志士)｢ﾀﾞﾒ人間でも 人間｣
[Exclusionist Karaoke Contest [middle of room]]
I'm a hopeless schmuck, but I'm still a person.
♪♪(志士)｢窓際でも 瀬戸際｣
I gaze out the window, but I'm still by the channel...
(隊士たち)ﾌﾝｯ…！
♪♪～
(土方)御用 改めである｡
真選組だ～!!
This is a raid!
We're the Shinsengumi!
(ざわめき)
(志士)真選組!? ﾃﾚﾋﾞｸﾙｰ引き連れて
なにが 御用改めだ～！
The Shinsengumi? You're with a television crew. What's up with that?!
ﾃﾒｴらこそ ｶﾗｵｹしながら
幕府を転覆させようとは➡
And you've got some nerve, singing karaoke while plotting to overthrow the government!
いい度胸だ～!!
Arrest them all!
１人残らず 召し取れ～!!
(隊士たち)おぉ～っ!!
(隊士)でやっ！
(志士)うわっ！
Why you?!
＜我々 取材班は この真選組に
24時間 完全密着し➡
For the next 24 hours, our camera crew will cover the Shinsengumi
その全貌を
明らかにしていこうと思う！＞
and give you the true story of what it's like on patrol.
(隊士)往生しろ～！
(志士)幕府の犬が～!!
Give it up!
You government dog!
♪♪～
Close up! 24 Hours with the Shinsengumi Elite Police!
(爆風音)
(志士たち)あぁっ…｡
(沖田)ﾀﾞﾒですよ
逃げたりしちゃ～｡
It's no use trying to run.
[Shinsengumi First Squad Captain]
[Sogo Okita]
あ～ かったりい～｡
How boring.
(志士)こ… この野郎… 寄るな！
[Why are the skies blue?]
You bastard!
Don't come near me! You'll never keep us down!
貴様らなどに 我々の志は…！
攘夷志士のくせに 芸者あげて
ﾁｬﾗﾁｬﾗしてんじゃねえよ｡
You're an exclusionist. Don't go prancing around with geisha!
あぁぁぁっ…！
…てや～っ!!
[Pink skies are cuter.]
♪♪～
Amazing!
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)すげっ…｡
[Shinsengumi Vice Chief]
[Toshiro Hijikata]
[Shinsengumi Chief]
[Isao Kondo]
(原田)あれ？ 近藤局長は？
Huh?
Where's Chief Kondo?
(隊士)あっ そういえば…｡
(隊士)どこへ行ったんだ？
Yeah, come to think of it...
Where did he go?
(土方)あの人は ｵﾚたちと違って
奥ゆかしいからな｡
He's a lot more refined than we are.
ﾃﾚﾋﾞの取材なんぞにゃ
用は ねえのさ｡
He said that he didn't want anything to do with a TV exposé.
(原田)お～ さすが 局長！
Wow. That's what I would have expected him to do!
今ごろは 幕府の お偉方と
談義してるか➡
Right now, he's probably having a discussion with someone important in the government or cleaning his sword alone.
一人静かに 刀の手入れでも
してんじゃねえか…｡
(近藤)どうせ ｵﾚなんて
ｹﾂ毛 ﾎﾞｰﾎﾞｰだしさぁ…｡
It's not gonna happen... besides, my butt hair is too thick.
(近藤)女に ﾓﾃるわけないんだよ｡
There's no way a girl would go out with me.
(近藤)はぁ～あ…｡
ﾀﾞﾒだな ｵﾚは…｡
I'm no good.
(お妙)そんなことないですよ｡
That's not true.
男らしくて ｽﾃｷじゃありませんか｡
You're just very manly!  And that's attractive, isn't it?
じゃあ 聞くけどさ
もし お妙さんの彼氏がさ…➡
Then let me ask you this...
If your boyfriend's...
ｹﾂが 毛だるまだったら
どうするよ？
rear end looked like an afro with a part down the middle, what would you do?
ｹﾂ毛ごと 愛します｡
I would love him, butt afro and all.
《近藤:菩薩…！
すべての不浄を包み込む…➡
What a goddess!  She purifies unclean things, just like a Bodhisattva.
まるで 菩薩だ！》
けっ… けっ… けっ… けっ…➡
Butt...butt...butt...but will you marry me!
結婚してください!!
えっ!?
["There Is Butt a Fine Line Between Persistence and Stubbornness"]
[Kodokan Dojo]
What?! Someone asked you to marry him?!
(新八)なに～っ!?
結婚 申し込まれたって～!?
ﾏｼﾞでございますか!? 姉上!!
Are you serious, Sis?!
ﾏｼﾞですよ…｡
お店のお客さんに 突然ね…｡
I'm serious.
Yesterday, out of the blue, a customer proposed.
で… なんと…？
So what did you say?
ﾌﾌ…｡ もちろん
丁重に お断わりしたけど…｡
Of course, I politely turned him down.
ﾋﾞｯｸﾘしたわ…｡
He sure took me by surprise!
初めて会ったのに あんなに
しつこく迫ってくるなんて…｡
I can't believe how stubborn he got about it, too.
((近藤:お妙さ～ん!!
Otae!
(お妙)ﾊｯ!!
んがっ…！))
In the end, he was so annoying,
あんまり しつこいから
鼻に ｽﾄﾚｰﾄきめて 逃げてきたの｡
I had to pop him in the schnoz and make a run for it.
そ… そうですか…｡
R-Really?
どんな人か ﾎﾞｸも見たかった…｡
(近藤)お妙さ～ん!!
I'd like to meet a guy like that.
Otae!
お妙さ～ん!!
ｵﾚと 結婚してくれ～!!
Otae! Marry me!
(近藤)一度や 二度
ﾌﾗれたくらいじゃ ｵﾚは倒れんよ！
I'm not the kind of man who takes "No" for an answer twice!
女はさ～！
愛するより 愛されるほうが➡
My mom says women find more happiness in being loved than in loving someone!
幸せなんだよ～!! って
母ちゃんが言ってた！
≪(岡っ引き)ｺﾗ～!!
Hey!
(岡っ引き)朝っぱらから
何やってんだ～!?
What are you doing up there so early in the morning?!
近所迷惑だ！
降りてこい この野郎!!
You're bothering the neighbors. Come down, you jackass!
(近藤)おまわりさん！
落ち着いてくれ!! ｵﾚは…➡
Relax, officer!
I...
ﾌｯ… ｵﾚは 泥棒は泥棒でも…➡
I may be a thief,
恋泥棒さ！
but I only steal hearts, okay?
(岡っ引き)
なに 満ち足りた顔してんだ！
Wipe that smug grin off your face!
全然 うまくねえんだよ！
とっとと降りてきやがれ～!!
What a weak comeback! Get down here right now!
Otae!
(近藤)お妙さ～ん！ 顔だけでも
出してくんないかな～!?
Won't you just show your angelic face at least?!
(近藤)あっ！ お妙さん!!
Otae!
(拍手)
(隊士たち)せいっ！
The Shinsengumi start their mornings early.
＜真選組の 朝は早い｡
いつ なんどき 出動が
かかっても対応できるよう➡
Training hard from early in the morning so they can jump into action at any time!
早朝から 訓練に励んでいるのだ＞
気合い入れろ～！
Put some spirit into it!
早朝訓練を ｻﾎﾞるﾔﾂは
切腹だぞ ｵﾗ～!!
Anyone who skips out on morning training will commit seppuku!
(隊士たち)せいっ…！
(原田)早朝か…｡
(隊士)早朝ね…｡
Early morning, huh?
Early morning.
副長が 早朝つったら
早朝なのよね…｡
If the vice chief says it's early morning, it's early morning.
(沖田の いびき)
(山崎)いや 早くないから！
This ain't early.
10 AM is not considered early in the morning!
午前10時は 早朝 って
言わないから！
ﾊﾞｶ野郎!! 人間 気合いがありゃあ
なんとでもなるんだよ！
Dimwit!
As long as a man has spirit, he can do anything!
これは 気合いじゃなくて
偽装でしょ？
This isn't spirit. This is stubbornness in disguise.
っていうか ﾃﾒｴは
また ﾐﾝﾄﾝか ｺﾗ～!!
Anyway, are you still playing badminton?!
ﾌｩ…｡
そういや 近藤さん➡
Come to think of it, I don't see Kondo today either...
今日も 見かけませんね｡
休暇でも とったんですかい？
Did he take a leave of absence?
ﾃﾒｴと 一緒にすんな！
Don't lump him in with you!
あの人のことだ… 大方 １人で
剣術の修業でもしてんのさ｡
This is Kondo we're talking about. He's probably training by himself.
Ahh. That's just what you'd expect from Chief Kondo.
おぉ～っ！ さすがは 近藤局長！
局長ともなると違うな…｡
(隊士)惚れ直すぜ…｡
He really is something!
I've fallen in love with him all over again.
姉上も 変なのに
惚れられちゃいましたね…｡
You've got a strange admirer, Sis.
ﾎﾝﾄ… 困っちゃうわ…｡
It really is a bother.
さてと… お夕食は…｡
Now then, dinner will be...
Eggs?! Sis!
ﾀﾏｺﾞ!? 姉上！ また ﾀﾏｺﾞ!?
Eggs again?!
好き嫌い 言わないの｡
ﾀﾏｺﾞは 栄養あるのよ｡
Don't be picky. Eggs have nutritional value.
いや～！
料理は ﾎﾞｸがしますから!!
I'll cook! You just buy the groceries!
姉上は 買い物だけしてください！
そう…｡
Okay.
Phew.
《だって…
姉上のﾀﾏｺﾞ焼きときたら➡
Her fried eggs
ﾀﾏｺﾞ焼きじゃなくて
かわいそうなﾀﾏｺﾞ…➡
aren't fried eggs. They're poor, innocent abused eggs.
だもんな…》
That's right.
Oh well.
(お妙)しかたないわね…｡
ﾌﾌ…｡
んっ？
ｷｬ～ｯ！
ああっ…！
[Go out with me for a hump.]
"Go out with me for a hump?"
ひとやま つきあえ って
意味わかんねえよ!!
What does that mean?!
(近藤)ぐぉ～っ!!
[I love you. -Isao Kondo]
ああっ…！
(近藤)お妙さん！
Oh.
Otae.
こう見えても
ｵﾚは ｽﾎﾟｰﾂﾏﾝなんだ！
I may not look it, but I'm an athlete.
趣味は ﾃﾆｽとｽｷｭｰﾊﾞﾀﾞｲﾋﾞﾝｸﾞかな！
I like tennis and scuba diving.
♪♪～
Glitter.
どっちかにしろや～！
この ど変態が～!!
Do one at a time, you freak!
The Shinsengumi have many different jobs.
＜真選組の仕事は
多岐にわたっている＞
♪♪～
＜大都会 江戸の交通整理も
その仕事の１つだ＞
Including directing traffic in the great city of Edo.
(ｸﾗｸｼｮﾝ)
Hey, you there! Who gave you permission to change direction?!
おい　ｺﾗ そこ！
誰の許可もらって➡
進路変更してんだ!?
逃げんじゃねえよ！
Don't run away! Anyone who runs is gonna get chopped!
逃げるﾔﾂは このｵﾚが
たたき斬るぞ～!!
(沖田)まぁまぁ 土方さん｡
Now, now, Hijikata.
土方さんは
気が短くていけねえや｡
Don't get mad.
ここは ｵﾚに任してくださいよ｡
Just leave this to me.
任せられっか!!
(発射音)
I'm not leaving anything to you!
(爆発音)
あ～あ｡ ﾎﾝﾄ 土方さんは
過激なんだから…｡
Hijikata, you sure have a violent streak.
ﾃﾒｴだろうが 総悟!!
責任なすりつけてんじゃねえよ!!
You should talk, Sogo! Don't try to pass it off on me!
…というわけなんですよ 銀さん｡
[Ran-Ran-Ran]
That's the story, Gin.
というわけじゃねえよ この野郎！
はぁ？
What do you mean by that, you bastard?
番組 始まって
もう 何分 経つよ？
How many minutes have passed since the show started?
こんなに経つまで
主人公のｵﾚに…➡
I'm the main character, but it's taken so long to get to me.
出番が ねえってのは
問題じゃねえのか!?
Doesn't anyone have a problem with me not being in the show?!
(店主)11分10秒｡
これ 『銀魂』だろ？
Eleven minutes, ten seconds.
This is Gin Tama, isn't it?
なぁ！ おい！ どうよ!?
Isn't it?
Hey!
Come on!
あん？ えぇっ!?
｢たま｣だけじゃ ｢ﾎﾟﾁ｣だよ～！
Right?!
Huh?!
It would be a flop if it was just "Tama."
ｵﾚが出なくて
なにが 『銀魂』だよ!!
What's the point in calling it Gin Tama if I'm not on screen?!
いや… 一応 今日の番組ﾀｲﾄﾙは➡
Well, it seems like the title for today's show is:
『完全密着！
武装警察 真選組24時!!』｡
"Close up! 24 Hours with the Shinsengumi Elite Police!"
…だそうですけど｡
What the hell?!
なにそれ!? 聞いてないよ！
I never heard about that!
銀さんが
やる気 出さないからですよ｡
That's because you can't be bothered to get moving.
このままじゃ ﾎﾝﾄに真選組が
主役のｱﾆﾒになっちゃいますよ｡
At this rate, the Shinsengumi are really going to be the stars of this anime.
ﾏｼﾞでか!? はっ！ そういや 今日➡
Really?!
Oh!
Now that you mention it, we didn't play the Gin Tama theme music!
『銀魂』のｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞ やってねえ！
あぶねえ あぶねえ…｡
This is bad. This is Gin Tama! I'm the star!
これ 『銀魂』だから！
ｵﾚ 主役だから～!!
Aren't you glad that someone wants to marry her?
よかったじゃねえか｡
嫁の もらい手があってよ～｡
帯刀してたってことは
幕臣か なんかだろ？
He's got a sword in his belt, so that means he's important at least, right?
This is your meal ticket, baby!
玉の輿じゃねえか｡
本性が ﾊﾞﾚないうちに
籍 入れとけ 籍｡
Get yourself hitched before he discovers what you're really like!
(お妙)それ どういう意味？
What's that supposed to mean?!
最初はね… そのうち
あきらめるだろうと思って➡
At first, I thought he was going to give up, so I didn't give it much thought.
たいして
気にしてなかったんだけど…｡
But... he's shown up no matter where I went.
(お妙)どこ行っても
ｱｲﾂの姿があって…｡
ﾎﾝﾄ 異常なのよ…｡
It hit me that he's not normal.
はい あと 30秒｡
All right, thirty seconds left.
はいは～い ﾗｽﾄｽﾊﾟｰﾄ！
All right, the home stretch!
Stop chewing, Kagura.
噛まないで 飲み込め 神楽！
頼むぞ！
Chug it.  Please!  I didn't being any cash!
金 持ってきてねえんだから！
聞いてんの!? ｱﾝﾀら!!
Are you two even listening?!
んだよ… ｵﾚに どうしろっての？
What? You expect me to do something?
仕事の依頼なら
出すもん出してもらわにゃ…｡
If you want me to take a job, then show me the money.
銀さん… ﾎﾞｸ もう ２か月
給料もらってないんですけど…｡
Gin, you know you haven't paid me in, like two months.
出るとこ 出てもいいんですよ｡
I could sue you.
出るとこ 出るってもな…｡
Can't pay you.  Even if we do go to court.
Come on. If you don't find some motivation you're gonna lose your spot as star of the show.
ほら やる気 出さないと主役が…｡
ｽﾄｰｶｰめ～！ どこだ～!!
成敗してくれるわ～!!
Stalker-Pervert, where are ya?! Come out and get your ass handed to you!
なんだ～!? この野郎 ｵﾗ～!?
やれるもんなら やってみろ～!!
What did you say?!
Bring it on if you can!
ﾎﾝﾄに いたよ…｡
ﾌﾝ！
He was really here.
Boy, you sure are stupid to pop up when someone calls for a stalker.
ｽﾄｰｶｰと呼ばれて 出てくるとは
ﾊﾞｶな野郎だ！
己が ｽﾄｰｶｰであることを
認めたか？
So you admit you're stalker?
ﾌﾝｯ｡ 人は皆 愛を求め
追い続けるｽﾄｰｶｰよ！
Everyone is a stalker in search of love.
ときに 貴様…
先ほどより お妙さんと➡
Listen jerk! A little while ago I saw you getting all chummy with Otae.
親しげに話しているが
いったい どういう関係だ？
Just what the hell is your relationship with her?
うらやましいこと 山の如しだ！
I'm uncontrollably jealous!
許婚です～｡
We're engaged.
私 この人と 秋に結婚するんです｡
そうなの？
I'm going to marry him in the fall.
Really?
(お妙)もう あんなことも
こんなこともしちゃってるんです｡
We're already lovers.  He's defiled me this way and that way and every other way.
だから 私のことは あきらめて｡
So give up already.
あ… あんなことも こんなことも
そんなこともだと～!?
Th-this and th-that? And other thing, too?!
いや…
そんなことはしてないですよ｡
No, they haven't done the other thing yet.
いや！ いいんだ お妙さん!!
Fine, Otae.
I don't care how skanky you are.
ｷﾐが
どんな人生を歩んでいようと➡
ｵﾚは ありのままのｷﾐを
受け止めるよ｡ ｷﾐが ｹﾂ毛ごと➡
I accept you all the same.
Huh?
Just like how you love me, hairy ass and all.
ｵﾚを愛してくれたように！
(お妙)愛してねえよ！
I don't love you!
…おい!! 銀髪ﾊﾟｰﾏ!!
Hey, you wavy-silver-haired bastard!
(近藤)お前が お妙さんの
許婚だろうと 関係ない！
It doesn't matter if you're Otae's fiancé!
(近藤)お前なんかより ｵﾚのほうが
お妙さんを愛している!!
I love Otae more than you ever can!
I'm calling you out!  Winner takes Otae!
ｵﾚと 決闘しろ!!
お妙さんをかけて!!
♪♪～
(お妙)あ～あ…｡
よけいなｳｿつかなきゃよかったわ｡
I shouldn't have made up such a pointless lie.
確かに なんだか かえって➡
Indeed. Seems to have just egged him on.
大変な状況に
なってる気がしますね…｡
(お妙)それに あの人 たぶん強い｡
And that guy must be pretty strong.
(お妙)決闘を前に
あの落ち着きぶりは➡
Look how relaxed he is right before your duel.
何度も 死線を
くぐり抜けてきた証拠よ｡
Like he's faced certain death many times before.
(神楽)心配いらないよ｡
銀ちゃん ﾋﾟﾝﾁのときは…➡
Don't worry.
If Gin's in danger... My umbrella will unleash hell on earth, Sis.
私の傘が 火を噴くね！ 姉御｡
殺さない程度にね｡
Try not to kill him.
Hey, four-eyes! Where'd he go?!
(近藤)おい ﾒｶﾞﾈ小僧！
ｱｲﾂは どうした!?
誰が ﾒｶﾞﾈ小僧だ！ なんか➡
Who are you calling "four-eyes"? He said he had to go to the can!
厠いってくるって
言ってましたけど！
That's awfully confident of him!
(近藤)ずいぶん 余裕 かまして
くれちゃってるじゃねえの！
♪♪～
＜我々 取材班は
町なかで暴れる➡
Our reporting team has received information about an unruly drunk downtown.
酔っ払いがいるという情報を得て
現場に向かった！＞
We've headed to the scene!
(ﾑｰさん)ﾊﾞ～ﾛ～! 昼間っから
酒 飲んじゃいけねえんかよ！
You idiot! Can't I drink during the day?
[Voice changed to protect his privacy.]
(ﾑｰさん)そういう法律
いつ できたんだよ～!!
Since when was it against the law?!
＜ そこには 江戸の守護者
真選組が すでに到着していて…➡
Edo's protectors, the Shinsengumi have already arrived.
到着して…➡
Arrived.
Arri...
到着…＞
＜今かよ!! 今 到着かよ！＞
Now?! They just got here?!
Bleep! Bleep!
♪♪(ﾑｰさんの鼻歌)
(沖田)そこの酔っ払い！
ﾑﾀﾞな抵抗はやめて 投降しなさい｡
Hey, you lush!
There's no point in putting up a fight. Surrender...
What?! Who're you calling a lush?!
(ﾑｰさん)なんだと～!?
誰が 酔っ払いだ～!?
(ﾑｰさん)こんなもん
飲んだうちに入んねえよ…！
This doesn't even count as drinking.
Boy!
土方さん 斬り殺していいっすか？
Hijikata, can we kill him?
まぁ 待て｡ ｶﾒﾗがあんだから➡
Wait.
There are cameras.
軽々しく 刃傷沙汰
起こすんじゃねえよ｡
Don't be so quick on the draw.
(ﾑｰさん)うっ…！ うぇぇ～っ!!
…ﾃﾒｴ ｵﾚのｽﾞﾎﾞﾝの裾に
飛沫が かかったぞ！
You bastard! You got puke on my pant leg.
(土方)どうしてくれ…｡
(隊士)おい みんな➡
What are you going to do about it?
Hey, everyone, hold Hijikata back!
土方さんを 押さえろ!!
(土方)ﾊﾞｶ野郎！ 放しやがれ!!
You imbeciles! Let me go!
I'm going to drag him around town and cut his head off!
ｺｲﾂは 市中引き回しのうえ
打ち首獄門だ～!!
Vice chief, calm down!
副長 抑えてください!!
(隊士)ｶﾒﾗ… ｶﾒﾗが回ってる！
The cameras are still rolling!
こんなとこ 撮ってんじゃねえよ!!
Don't film this.
(町人)何やってんだい？
What are they doing?
(町人)いやぁ
なんでも 決闘らしいぜ｡
Well, it looks like a duel!
決闘？ へぇ こんなご時勢に
珍しいじゃねえか！
A duel? Oh?
Don't see that much these days!
え～ おせんにｷｬﾗﾒﾙ…｡
Rice crackers and caramel candy.
ｺｰﾗ いかがっすかぁ？
How about a soda?
(近藤)おい まだか！ まさか
逃げたんじゃねえだろうな!!
Hey, is he ready yet?! He didn't run off, did he?!
≪ﾊﾞｰｶ ﾃﾒｴ程度の相手に
逃げやしねえよ！
Dumbass. I wouldn't run away from an opponent like you.
来たか… 遅すぎるぞ！
大のほうか!?
You came!
You're late! Were you taking a dump?!
ﾋｰﾛｰが 大なんて
するわけねえだろ｡
Taking a dump wouldn't be very heroic.
糖のほうだ｡
I took some sugar.
[Sugar]
血糖値の高いﾋｰﾛｰなんて
聞いたことねえよ｡
Never heard of a hypoglycemic hero before!
いいねぇ… 夕日だ｡
What a nice sunset.
♪♪～
決闘は 夕日に限るぜ…｡
Duels are best at sunset.
ﾌﾝｯ 銀髪ﾊﾟｰﾏのわりには
風流なことを言いやがる｡
You've got some grace for a man with wavy silver hair.
ﾃﾒｴも ｺﾞﾘﾗにしちゃ
人間の言葉がうめえじゃねえか｡
And you speak pretty well for a gorilla.
ｺﾞ… ｺﾞﾘﾗじゃないから！
I-I'm not a gorilla! I may look like one, but I'm not.
ｺﾞﾘﾗに似てるかもしれないけど
違うから！
まあいい｡
じゃあ そろそろ始めっか｡
Whatever. Shall we get started?
(近藤)で… 獲物はどうするよ？
Choose your weapons.
真剣が使いたければ 貸すぞ｡
If you want to use a real sword, I'll lend you one.
お前の好きにしろ｡
ｵﾚは ｺｲﾂで十分だ｡
Whatever you like.
This is good enough for me.
このまま やろうや｡
なめてんのか 貴様…｡
Let's do this.
Are you tryin' to make a fool out of me, butthead?
悪いが…
人の人生懸けて勝負できるほど➡
Sorry, but I'm not noble enough to duel over someone else's life.
大層な人間じゃないんでね｡
代わりと言っちゃなんだが
ｵﾚの命を懸けよう｡
As a substitute, I'll wager my life instead.
I'm going to wager my life instead of Otae's.
お妙の代わりに ｵﾚの命を懸ける｡
ﾃﾒｴが勝っても お妙は
お前のものには ならねえが➡
Even if you win, you don't get Otae.
ｼﾞｬﾏなｵﾚは消える…｡
But I'll be out of your way...
あとは 口説くなり なんなり
好きにすりゃいい｡
You can court her or whatever you'd like afterwards.
もちろん ｵﾚが勝ったら
お妙から 手を引いてもらう｡
Of course, if I win you'll keep your paws off her.
(ざわめき)
《自分の命を
白刃の元にさらして➡
He's going to put himself in the path of a naked blade,
負けても 私に危害を
及ぼさないようにするつもり!?》
and protect me even if he loses?!
(お妙)ちょっと… やめなさい！
銀さん!!
Wait!  Stop right there!  Gin!
(近藤)ﾌｯﾌﾌﾌﾌ…｡
いい男だな お前｡
You sure are a man amongst men.
いや… 女子より
男にﾓﾃる男とみた｡
I think you're more popular with men than women.
小僧！ お前の木刀を貸せ!!
Boy!  Lend me your wooden sword!
ﾃﾒｴも いい男じゃねえか｡
You're a good man, too.
使えよ…
ｵﾚの自慢の愛刀 洞爺湖だ｡
Use this. It's my favorite sword, Lake Toya.
Gin!
銀さん！
勝っても負けても
お互い 遺恨はねえな！
Win or lose, we won't hold any grudges, right?
ああ｡ 純粋に男として勝負だ｡
You got it.
Now, let's have a fair fight, man to man.
♪♪～
Let's go!
いざ！
尋常に!!
A fair...
(２人)勝負!!
duel!
Huh?
あれ？ あれぇ～っ!?
What?!
ちょっと待て！ 先っちょが…｡
Hold on a second!  The blade!  The t-t-tip!
あれ？ さ… 先っちょがぁ!!
えぇ～いっ!!
It's missiiinnggg!
(近藤)ねえぇ～っ!!
うぁ…｡
Sucker...sweeter than Tianjin roasted chestnuts.
甘え… 天津甘栗より甘え！
敵から獲物を借りるなんざよぉ！
I can't believe you'd accept a weapon from your enemy!
厠で削っといた…｡
When I went to the john,
ぶん回しただけで
折れるくらいにな！
I scored it with a deep cut, so deep it would split just from being swung.
貴様… そこまでやるか！
You bastard!  You'd go that far?!
こんなことのために➡
Only a total dork would try to settle something so important like this.
誰かが 何かを失うのは
ﾊﾞｶげてるぜ！
すべて 丸く収めるにゃ
ｺｲﾂが いちばんだろ？
Isn't it better to just mellow out and talk things through?
これ… 丸いか？
This is mellowing out?
よぉ！ どうだい？
この 鮮やかな手口…うはっ!!
Hey. Wha'dya think of my brilliant plan?
I've lost all faith in you!  That's not samurai spirit!
見損なったよ！
侍の風上にも置けないね!!
You feel satisfied now, cheater?!  Coward!
あんなことして 勝って
嬉しいんですか？ この卑怯者！
お前 姉ちゃん守ってやったのに
そりゃ ないんじゃないの!?
What are you saying! I defended your sister.
もう帰る！
二度と私の前に 現れないで!!
I'm going home!
I never want to see your face again!
しばらく 休暇もらいます！
I'm going on vacation for a while.
ﾌｯﾌﾌ…｡
Everything ended well.
《すべて 丸くね…
でも なんだかんだで➡
But it looks like Gin got the worst of it.
銀さんが いちばん
泥かぶっちゃったわね》
うっ うっ…
なんで こんな惨めな気分？
I feel like warmed over kitty litter.
不器用な人…｡
What a klutz.
But, I'm starting to get you.
でも…
私は ちゃんとわかってますから｡
＜真選組副長 土方 十四郎｡
彼は 激務が終わったあとも➡
The Shinsengumi's vice chief, Toshiro Hijikata.
He quietly patrols the city by himself even after a rough job.
一人 静かに
市中を見回りしている｡
今 彼のその目には
いったい 何が映っているのか＞
What could he be seeing right now?
…あっ｡
なんの騒ぎだ？
(町人)いやぁ なんでも➡
What's the fuss?
Well, there was a duel over a woman.
女 取り合って
決闘したそうですぜ｡
女で決闘だぁ？
A duel over a woman?
くっだらねえ どこのﾊﾞｶが… あっ｡
How stupid! What idiot would...
(土方)近藤局長？
Chief Kondo.
Chief Kondo?
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)近藤局長？
あれが真選組の局長➡
That's the Shinsengumi's chief...
近藤 勲さんですか？
Isao Kondo?
ﾃﾒｴ ﾊﾞｶ！ なに撮ってんだぁ!!
You idiot! What are you filming?!
＜ こうして
真選組の活躍によって➡
Because of the work of the Shinsengumi, peace in Edo has been upheld.
江戸の平和は 守られているのだ｡
ﾎﾝﾄか!?＞
Really?
[Close up! 24 hours with the Shinsengumi Elite Police!]
[The End]]
Third year, class Z, Ginpachi-sensei! After these messages.
[Preview]
Where's the guy that attacked Chief Kondo?!
He may be a gorilla, but he's our leader!
A silver-haired samurai? You're that guy!
The next episode: "Fighting Should Be Done With Fists."
[A battle begins for the Odd Jobs Trio!  What happens next?!]
[Do JUMP anime always have to have battles?]
[Third year, Class Z]
[Ginpachi-sensei]
Third year, class Z!
Ginpachi-sensei!
[Third year, Class Z]
Hey. Close your textbooks for a moment.
Listen, Shimura's recorder has been stolen.
The thief may be in another class,
but I'm lazy, so I'll just assign blame to someone here.
[MIND YOUR SUGAR LEVELS]
Whoever stole it raise your hands.  It's okay to lie!
If you do it now, Shimura and I will forgive you
if you shove the recorder up your butt and play a chorus of "Please Give Me Wings."
Sensei, we'd never grow wings if we did that.
Change the song to Match's hit song, "Settle It."
All right. Match's hit song, "Shy About My Butt Hair".
Sensei, I don't know how that song goes.
You just made up that song title.
Okay, someone lend me a recorder. I'll play it.
[Chikuwa]
Sensei, use mine. It's broken and can only play the note "fa."
Your head is what's broken.
♪♪～
Hey, I don't care who, somebody lend me your recorder.  A cute girl preferably.
No way!  It'll end up tasting like cigarettes.
お～い！
ちょっと 教科書 閉じろ～！
実はな～
志村の たて笛が盗まれた｡
I told you, this isn't a cigarette. It's a lollipop.
犯人は 他のｸﾗｽに
いるかもしれねえが➡
Smoke doesn't come out of lollipops.
面倒なんで ｸﾗｽ内で
適当に見繕うことにした｡
That's because I've licked it so much.
盗んだﾔﾂは 正直に 手を挙げろ｡
ｳｿでもいいぞ！ 今なら 志村も
ｹﾂに たて笛を突っ込んで➡
Anyway, one of you girls, lend me your recorder! I'll lick and play it.
No way in hell!
『翼をください』を
ﾜﾝｺｰﾗｽ演奏するだけで➡
Cut it out, girls! Sensei is desperate to find the thief.
許してくれるって｡
(土方)先生！
そんなﾏﾈしたら ｵﾚたち
一生 翼なんて生えません！
Sensei, use mine. It's okay if it starts to smell like cigarettes.  I have two of them.
ﾏｯﾁの名曲
『ｹｼﾞﾒなさい』にしてください！
わかった～｡ ﾏｯﾁの名曲
｢ｹﾂ毛ｻﾞｼｬｲ｣でいこう！
Why do you have two of them?
(長谷川)先生！
曲調が よくわかりません｡
ってか そんな曲ねえよ！
Huh?  Hold on a second.  Are you really going to do it?  Ah!
しょうがねえな…｡
誰か 笛 貸せ｡ ｵﾚが吹くから｡
Sensei, can I go to the nurse's office?
(神楽)先生！ 私の どうぞ｡
壊れて ﾌｧの音しか出ないけど｡
[The End]
壊れてるのは お前の頭だ｡
お～い 誰でもいいから
笛を貸せ～！
できれば 女子！
(女子)ｲﾔで～す！
(女子)ﾀﾊﾞｺ臭くなりそうだから｡
だ～から これは ﾀﾊﾞｺじゃなくて➡
ﾚﾛﾚﾛｷｬﾝﾃﾞｨｰだって言ってんだろ？
(女子)ﾚﾛﾚﾛｷｬﾝﾃﾞｨｰから
煙は出ません｡
だ～から すご～く
ﾚﾛﾚﾛﾚﾛﾚﾛしてるから➡
煙が 出てるんだってば…｡
いいから 女子 笛 貸せ！
ｵﾚが ﾚﾛﾚﾛ吹くから！
(女子たち)絶対 ｲﾔです!!
(近藤)
いいかげんにしろよ 女子!!
先生は 犯人 捜そうと
必死なんだぞ!!
先生！ ｵﾚの使ってください!!
大丈夫っす！ ﾔﾆ臭くなっても
ｵﾚ ２本 持ってるんで!!
…なんで ２本も 持ってるんだ？
ｳﾌｯ｡
(近藤)ちょっと待って｡
ﾏｼﾞでやんの!? ｷﾞｬ～～ｯ!!
先生 保健室 行っていいですか？